Email: anblaziak@gmail.com

# ANNA BŁAZIAK

Full Stack Web Developer

Portfolio: https://aniablaziak.github.io/annablaziak-portfolio/

GitHub: https://github.com/aniablaziak

### **PROFILE**

Full Stack JavaScript Web Developer experienced with working in Agile and crossfunctional teams. Enthusiastic learner with excellent communication skills and a great eye for detail. Passionate about great user experience, creative problem solving and clean, readable code.

**Technical Proficiencies:** HTML, CSS, JavaScript (ES6), Node.js, Express, Elixir, Phoenix, React, GraphQL, PostgreSQL, Handlebars.js, Sass, Jest, Travis CI, Figma, Heroku, Git & GitHub

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Junior Full Stack Developer, Made by Many

SEP 2019 - NOV 2019, LONDON, UK

- Introduced to the Elixir programming language by building an Instagram replica web application using the Phoenix framework and GraphQL on the backend and React with CSS-in-JS (Styled Components) on the frontend

### Developer Intern, Made by Many

JUL 2019 - SEP 2019, LONDON, UK

- Participated in a 10-week internship at a digital product consultancy, developing a functional product prototype, a web based application built with React, Node.js, PostgreSQL and Styled Components
- Learnt the process and principles of user-centred design
- Participated in defining and designing a digital product based on user research and user testing
- Acquired first-hand experience of working in a cross-functional team
- Worked and collaborated closely with the client

### Software Development Student, Founders & Coders

MAR 2019 - JUN 2019, LONDON, UK

- Participated in an 18-week, full stack web development course with an emphasis on peer-led learning and **pair programming**
- Gained practical experience of working on projects in Agile teams
- Built full stack projects in collaborations with charities and NGOs with the use of **design thinking**, **user research** and **user testing**
- Hosted and mentored meetups for prospect future course students
  Areas of learning: JavaScript (ES6), Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, Semantic HTML, REST
  APIs, Sass, React, BEM, Test Driven Development, Continuous Integration

## Project Management Intern, Creative Translation

SEP 2018 - DEC 2018, LONDON, UK

Project Management Intern at a translation agency specialising in marketing translation, working with brands such as Airbnb, PayPal, Norwegian Airlines, to name a few. My experience working as a Project Manager in the translation industry taught me excellent time management skills, creative problem solving, managing working to tight deadlines and maintaining an impeccable eye for detail. It also strengthened my communication skills and empathetic approach to the product audience.

#### **EDUCATION**

### **BA (Hons) Translation**

SEP 2016 – JUN 2018
London Metropolitan University, United Kingdom
BA English Studies (specialising in translation)
OCT 2014 – JUN 2016
Adam Mickiewicz University, Poland

#### **ADDITIONAL INFO**

I am passionate about diversity and inclusivity in the tech community and have been mentoring at Codebar, a weekly meet up enabling people from underrepresented groups to learn programming.

Here are some of tech conferences and meetups I have attended recently: Half Stack Conference 2018, ffconf 2018, // TODO Conf 2018
Front-end London, // TODO, JSMonthly, CSS London